谢谢你  我的朋友
Thank you my friend.
shad2前情回顾
不客气
Pleasure.
保重
Take care.
你不该在睡觉前看恐怖电影的
You shouldn't watch scary movies so close to bedtime.
凯特  杰米
Kate? Jamie!
爸爸
Dad!
-你替他辩护  -你跟我一样清楚
- You're defending him. - You know as well as I do,
无论好坏  每个人都有权申辩
for good or bad, everyone deserves a defence.
伯顿先生不能以律师身份出庭
Mr Burton will not be in court.
他是目击者  无论如何都不能代表检方
As he's a witness, he cannot act for the Crown in any way.
所以他只能看着
So he just has to watch.
福伊尔有个储物间  有人帮他接管了
Foyle had a storage unit. Someone took it on after him.
要是调查没有进展
If something's not turning up,
就意味着你要换个角度入手
you need to look for it somewhere else.
你当天晚上做的晚餐是什么
And what did you make for dinner that night?
奶油培根意面
Spaghetti carbonara!
我应该更拼命地跟他打
I should've fought him harder.
杰米  你在说什么
Jamie, What are you saying?
我抓伤了他的头
I scratched his head.
你用手去抓他了
You scratched him with your hands?
-然后我躲起来了  -你挪过位置
- And then I hid. - You moved?!
法医在小屋里找到了DNA
"The forensic team just found DNA at the cottage."
福伊尔的DNA吗
Foyle's?
他们想见面谈
"They want to meet."
你在发现妻子的震惊和悲伤之中
In the shock and trauma of finding your wife,
你看向窗外  看到一个男人
you look up at the window and see a man
如果此人消失  则对你非常有利
whose absence from your life would be very useful indeed,
但并不是他  对吗  伯顿先生
but it wasn't that man, was it, Mr Burton?
只是你希望是他
You just wanted it to be.
-谢谢  早安  -早安  兰伯特医生
- Thanks. Morning! - Good morning, Doctor Lambert.
对不起我迟到了  给我提个醒儿
Sorry I'm late. Remind me...
-低数值DNA  凯特·伯顿  -想起来了
- Low-count DNA. Kate Burton. - Oh, yeah.
今天的证词要简短直接
Straight and short this morning.
他们会在低数值上面为难你
They'll try and trip you on the low count.
回答简洁明了就好
Keep your answers simple.
谢谢提醒  这种事我已经做过三四百次了
Thanks for the tip. I've only done this three or 400 times.
这种分析是否可以证明
Did this analysis prove conclusively
在小屋发现的DNA
that the DNA discovered in the cottage
与某个人的DNA吻合
matches that of a particular individual?
-可以  -与谁的DNA吻合
- It did. - Whose DNA did the sample match?
我们发现该DNA与利亚姆·福伊尔先生吻合
We matched the sample to the DNA of Mr Liam Foyle.
我们的检测过程十分严格
We are very stringent about our quality controls.
对于工作向来一丝不苟
We take our job extremely seriously.
这样我们就放心了
That is very reassuring.
去年检察署起诉福伊尔先生时
Were you responsible for analysing
是你们负责检验案子的DNA样本吗
DNA samples in connection with Crown vs Foyle last year?
我想是的
I believe so.
你想是的
You believe so?
是我们负责的
Yes, we were.
为了做那份检验  我委托人的DNA样本
And in order to do that, samples of my client's DNA
会被送到你们实验室进行分析检测  对吧
would've been sent to and processed by your lab, is that correct?
-是的  有个...  -谢谢
- Well, yes, there's a...  - Thank you.
所以当时我委托人的DNA
So my client's DNA, at that time,
如同老房子里的灰尘
would've been effectively distributed
撒满了你们的实验室  对吧
throughout that lab like dust through an old house?
-法官阁下  -我想你的问话是有目的的吧
- My Lord! - I take it this is leading somewhere?
马上就说到了  法官阁下
I'm just arriving now, My Lord.
兰伯特医生  我有份你们实验室的宣誓证词
Dr Lambert, I have a sworn statement from your laboratory
其中指出本月12日  所有的无菌房
that confirms a deep clean was performed in all clean-room areas
都进行了一次彻底清理
on the 12th of this month.
-你提前进行了清理  为什么  -搞什么
- You brought the schedule forward. Why was that? - Oh, come on!
梅菲尔德先生
Mr Mayfield...
兰伯特医生  请回答
Dr Lambert, if you please...
我们定期进行清理
We conduct regular cleaning.
最近决定要增加
We recently decided to increase
-清理次数  -为什么要提前进行
- the number of cleans... - Why was the schedule brought forward?
我注意到你们的日常清理都是
I notice that your cleaning schedule is normally
严格按规定执行的  所以肯定有事发生
enacted on a clear and regulated basis, so something must've happened.
有这个必要
It was necessary.
你们是否正在实验室里
Are you or are you not in the process of an internal investigation
针对污染程度进行内部调查
into the viability of contaminants within the laboratory?
请回答是或不是
Please answer yes or no.
但我怎么回答...
But you can't answer...
是
Yes.
你是担心你们的错误率过高吗
Are you concerned about your failure rate?
我是不是...谁不担心错误率的问题
Am I...? Everyone's concerned about their failure rate!
-整个行业都担心  -谢谢
- It's an industry-wide concern! - Thank you.
法官阁下  我们先前可不知道这个
My Lord, this is new information.
确实应该早些公布出来
It should've been disclosed, certainly.
毫无疑问的是
What's clear beyond doubt is,
该DNA证据是完全不能采信的
this DNA evidence is utterly compromised.
-你得阻止她  -有点为时过晚
- You have to stop her. - It's a wee bit late for that.
她那是颠倒黑白  混淆是非
She's twisting the facts around to make them wrong.
倒是干得挺不错的
Doing a good job of it, too.
要是没有DNA证据  我们还有什么
If we don't have this DNA, then what do we have?
麻烦
A problem.
奶油培根意面
Spaghetti carbonara
餐后甜点是北极雪卷
and an Arctic roll for afters.
莫里斯女士  那是辩方关心的问题
Miss Morris, that's a matter for defence counsel.
我只想问你储物间搜查的结果
All I want to ask you about is the search of your storage unit,
而不是不在场证明  尽管不怎么样
not the defence alibi, such as it is.
-请如实回答我的问题  -法官阁下
- Please stick to the matter at hand. - My Lord!
赶紧问  梅菲尔德先生
Get on with it, Mr Mayfield.
莫里斯女士  你租了储物间吗
Miss Morris, you maintain a contract with this storage facility?
是的
I do, yes.
几天前警方搜查你的储物间时
And when these premises were searched by the police a few days ago,
发现了一双12号的靴子
a pair of size-12 boots was recovered from your unit,
-是吗  -是的  在另一个储物间
- isn't that right? - Yes, er, the other unit.
是你的靴子吗  对你来说好像有点大啊
Are these your boots? They seem rather large for you!
什么另一个储物间
What other unit?
法官阁下  这是新证据
My Lord, this is new information!
所有新证据昨天都已经告知辩方律师了
All new information was given to my learned friend yesterday.
证物连续性  法官阁下
Chain of continuity, My Lord...
庭警
Usher.
那是针对艾琳·莫里斯储物间内物品的搜查令
The warrant was for Eileen Morris's possessions in the storage unit.
-他们无权搜查F38  只有F37  -如果
- They had no authority to search F38. Only F37. - If...
搜查F38是不合法的
The search of F38 was unlawful.
如果辩方对证物有疑问
If defence had a problem with the evidence,
应该在适当时间提出
they should've argued it at the appropriate time.
我们刚得知此事
The issue has only just come to light.
福伊尔以前用过F37的事实与本案有关
Foyle's previous use of F37 connects him to it.
符合证物连续性
It falls within the chain of continuity.
F38则是完全不相关的
F38 was entirely separate!
法官阁下  我理所应当请您
Judge, obviously I will ask you
依照第78条排除这一非法物证
to exclude this evidence under Section 78.
它们就挨在一起  这...
It was the unit next door! It...
对于你的请求  我当然同意
And should you request, I will no doubt accede.
那我建议  法官阁下
Then, I respectfully submit, My Lord,
无须答辩
there is no case to answer.
由于缺乏可信证据
In the absence of any viable evidence
明明有令人信服的证据
There is compelling evidence!
目击者证词来自一个伤心的人
The eyewitness evidence of a broken man,
独自在黑暗中  情绪失常
alone and devastated in the dark...
我听过了辩方律师
Having heard arguments from counsel
就本次庭审中证据可信度的意见
as to the strength of the evidence at this stage of the trial,
作出以下结论
I have concluded the following...
供陪审团参考
There is insufficient evidence
继续庭审的证据不足
for the case to continue for your consideration.
因此我建议
For that reason, on my direction,
你们可作出无罪判决
you will return a verdict of not guilty.
根据法官阁下的建议
On His Lordship's direction,
你们认为被告有罪吗
do you find the defendant not guilty?
无罪
Not guilty.
-是陪审团的一致裁决吗  -是的
- And is that the verdict of you all? - Yes.
全体起立
All rise.
福伊尔先生  你可以离开被告席了
Mr Foyle, you may leave the dock.
-恭喜  -谢谢
- Congratulations. - Oh, thanks.
玛格丽特
Margaret...
谢谢你  我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
不客气  保重
Pleasure. Take care.
你没事吧  伙计  抱歉  脚滑了
Are you all right there, mate? Sorry, my foot slipped.
你没事吧
Are you all right? Yeah?
杰米
Jamie...
她成功了  开酒
Ah, she blows! Pull!
表现完美  一级棒
A consummate performance. First class.
这是给你的
This is for you.
你值得拥有
I believe you've earned it.
还有酒哦
Pretty juicy, too!
谢谢
Ooh! Thank you.
-瓦迪姆  -失陪一下
- Vadim! - Excuse me.
威尔先生
Mr Will.
你看起来不错
You're looking well.
你妻子的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear about your wife.
-谢谢  -有什么能帮忙的...
- Thank you. - If there is anything I can do for you...
你几点下班
What time do you finish work?
我克隆得很快
I clone it fast.
shad2姓名  利亚姆·迈克尔·福伊尔
shad2持卡类型  借记卡
shad2卡号  4012 8888 8888 1881
你要的地名  本阿力金
The name you wanted - Beinn Alligin.
抱歉  我就想过来...
Hi. Look, sorry, I just wanted to come and...
我也不知道我到底来干什么
I'm not sure why I came, actually.
那人就是那个谁吗
Was that who I think it was?
我以为你开庆功会去了
I thought you'd be out celebrating.
没有
No, just...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-只是...  -你的工作
- It's just... - Your job.
我没有恶意
Look, no hard feelings.
-我想说...  -你自己小心吧  玛吉
- By which I mean -Watch yourself, Maggie.
我能...
Can I...
我今晚能去你那儿吗
Can I come round tonight, please?
我好害怕
I'm freaking out!
我认为这太不合适了
"I think this is most inappropriate."
得了吧  你还认为
Oh, come on, think...
他怎么知道的  他不可能知道
How did he know? There's no way he could've known!
如果你那么担心
"If you're that concerned,
-我建议你打电话叫警察  -天哪
- I suggest you call the police." - Oh, God!
天哪  我刚才完全...
Oh, God, I've just completely...
我们还有机会可以上诉
We have a window for appeal.
-可能现在不行  但是...  -得了吧
- Maybe not now, but... - Come on!
-可希望总是...  -算了  我们输了
- No, optimism was never... - Forget it. We lost.
结束了
It's over.
威尔
Will!
要来吗
Are you coming?
-我以前都不知道这地方  -是啊
- I never knew about this place. - Yeah,
凯特的堂兄偶尔借我们一用
Kate's cousin lets us use it every now and again.
不如开瓶酒  想喝吗
Cracking bottle of wine inside, if you're interested?
找你可真是大费周章
It took some real sleuthing to find you.
你知道我的行事风格  华生
You know my methods, Watson.
-红的还是白的  -你选
- Red or white? - Er... You chose.
你怎么样  丹尼
How are you, Danny?!
见了你感觉好多啦  哥们
All the better for seeing you, mate!
-帮忙倒进锅里  -活的哟
- Pop those in the pot, would you? - That's alive, alive.
活的才对嘛
Now you're talking.
你煮面我做酱料
Ah, here! You pasta, me sauce.
这不需要许可证吗
Don't you need a permit for those?
潮区打渔是公共权利  1863年马尔科森
Public right to fish in tidal waters - Malcomson v O'Dea, 1863,
之前还有大宪章
before that, the Magna Carta.
说实话  大宪章里从未提过
To be fair, it's not mentioned at
只是大家都这么以为而已
all in the Magna Carta, everyone just thinks it was.
所以严格来讲  我们现在是在违法
So strictly speaking, right now, we just broke the law.
准确地说  是你违法
Well, to be precise, you did!
可你现在也是从犯
Except now, you're an accessory.
那我呢
What about me?
-大概只会警告  -多谢了
- Probably just a caution. - Thanks!
不客气
You're very welcome!
别唧唧歪歪了  快倒酒
Stop crying and pour some wine.
更别提民事诉讼
Not even a civil suit!
不要往那方向想了
We're not going in that direction.
就算我们告倒他  也没人是赢家
Even if we get him, no-one wins.
又不能让她起死回生
It's not going to bring her back.
那我们就这么坐着
So, we're just going to sit here, then?
你最近还忙吗
Are you keeping busy?
有份事务所经理的工作
I've been offered Chambers Manager at Citadel.
曼彻斯特那边
Manchester.
你知道那边怎么对待女王公园巡游者的粉丝吧
You do know what they do to QPR supporters there, don't you?!
让你受牵连我真抱歉  丹尼
I'm sorry you had to take that fall, Danny.
你突然消失我们可都担心了一阵子
You had us all worried for a minute, disappearing like that.
为什么
Why's that?
你一向井井有条的
You always seem so planned.
你是没瞧见我接送孩子上下学
You haven't seen the school run.
闲着不做事不是你的风格
I mean, it's not like you to do anything on the fly.
这才是我  丹尼
Well, that's me all over, Danny.
处处惊喜
I'm just full of surprises.
到爱丁堡要多久
How long does it take to get to Edinburgh?
照你这样开车  十分钟
Ten minutes, the way you drive.
别开得飞起来
Try not to take off, OK.
我会尽快回来  替我照顾好奶奶
I'll be back as soon as I can. Look after Granny for me.
-爸爸  -说
- Dad... - Yeah?
你在发抖
You're shaking.
如果你真的考虑过来
Look, I mean, if you really were thinking of coming here,
我们当然非常乐意有你加入
we'd, obviously, be very interested in having you join the set.
不  我来看看  我家人需要换个环境
No, I'm actively looking. My family needs a change of scene so...
全家来住  这可是个好地方
Oh, well, for families, it's a lovely place!
您在这期间不妨租车四处转转
You should rent a car and drive around a bit while you're here,
-看看风景  -我或许会的
- see the scenery. - I might just do that.
-要点儿什么  -可以借用下洗手间吗
- What would you like? - Hi. Do you mind if I use your loo?
多谢
Thanks.
如今的法律怎么界定私闯民宅
What's the law on home invasion these days?
我有点儿不清楚了
I'm a little cloudy.
在自己家中受到陌生人惊吓
What's a proportionate response to someone
正常的是什么反应
surprised in their home by a stranger?
我有事要问你
I need to ask you something.
我在脸书上
I'm on Facebook.
我知道
I know.
你都来了
You're here now,
想问我什么就问吧
so you can ask me whatever you like.
你什么时候打定主意要杀我妻子的
When did you decide to kill my wife?
拜托了  我想知道
Please, I need to know.
你杀她时  她是不是很快就死了
When you killed her, did she die quickly?
你这是在和我玩角色扮演吗
Are you playing a character? Are you?
你觉得你现在是居高临下俯视众生吗
Are you all the way up there, looking all the way down here?
还是你觉得我有那么一点弱智
And do you think I'm a little bit stupid?
你这样子就不对了
You're going about this all wrong.
这种事不是你最在行吗
Well, you're the expert.
你什么时候决定要杀我妻子的
When did you decide to kill my wife?
你的脑子啊
You and your brain!
近距离看过大脑吗
Have you ever seen a brain up close?
样子就像一颗花椰菜
It looks like a cauliflower.
大脑皮层就像糖霜一样
The neural cortex looks like icing.
据说这一点区分了我们和动物
They say it's what separates us from the animals.
但我们也是动物  哺乳动物
But we are animals. We're mammals.
就像狮子
Like a lion.
你总不会怪一头狮子野性难驯吧  威尔
You wouldn't blame a lion for being a lion, would you, Will?
而且还是你亲手将他放出笼子的
Especially if you were the one who let him out.
你是怎么过下去的
How do you live with yourself?
自我谅解
I forgive myself.
你又是怎么过下去的
How do you live with yourself?
你还真是聪明
You're very clever!
我的笔
My pen...
快把笔拿来
Get the pen!
救护车
Ambulance.
是个椭圆的管子
It's an oval tube.
椭圆管  没错  没错
Oval tube! Yes! Yes!
-管身是灰色末端是橙色  -没错
- It's sort of grey with an orange end. - Yeah. That's it.
我现在开免提
I'm putting you on speaker.
-能听到我说话吗  -听得到
- Can you still hear me? - Yes, I can hear you.
-管子拿好了吗  -好了
- Are you holding the tube? - Yeah.
-用拳头握紧管子  -好的
- Now put your fist around the tube. - OK.
把橙色尖端对准大腿
Hold the orange tip near the thigh.
-他穿着裤子  -针能刺进去
- He has his trousers on! - The needle will go through the cortex.
把橙色尖端对准大腿  另一只手
Hold the orange tip near his thigh, with your other hand
-把蓝色的安全阀摘掉  -搞定
- pull off the blue safety release. - Ok. Done it.
现在把尖端用力刺进大腿直到听到咔哒声
Now, swing and firmly push the tip against the thigh until it clicks.
再保持十秒钟  明白了吗
And hold it there for ten seconds. Did you get that?"
刺进去  咔哒声  等一会儿  我开始了
Swing, click, wait. OK. Here goes.
这是什么声音
What was that?
应该是针杆装置的声音  里面装了弹簧
You probably heard the needle mechanism. It's spring-loaded.
-好的  -肾上腺素笔里的药剂
- OK. - The drug in the EpiPen
应该能在救护车到前保持他体征平稳
should keep him steady 'till the ambulance gets to you.
-你还在听吗  -在听
- Are you still with me? - Yeah. I'm here.
你做得很好
You're doing great.
-现在呢  -可以拿出来了
- What now? - OK, you can take it out.
看下针管  能看到红色长条吗
Look at the barrel. Is there a red strip visible on the barrel?
有的话就说明药剂打进去了
That will tell you that the drug went in.
稍等下
Er, hang on. Hang on.
我看不清
I can't see it!
刻度上方有个小窗
Just above the writing, there's a window.
没错  找到了  在这儿
Oh, yes! Yes, yes, yes, it's there!
病人有反应吗
Is the patient responding?
先生  先生  还在吗
Sir? Sir? Hello?
有人在听吗
Anybody hear me?
有人吗
Hello?
有人在听吗
Anybody there?
先生  在听吗
Hello, sir?
能听得到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
-没什么大碍吧  -没事  就被烟呛了
- Are you all right? - Yeah, just a bit of smoke.
-只有你们两个人吗  -是的
- Just the two of you up there? - Yeah.
血管舒张  毛细管渗漏
Showing vasodilation. Capillary leak.
-他不会有事吧  -肩部失血过多
- Is he going to be OK? - Bad shoulder bleed here.
好吧  我们先保证他呼吸顺畅
All right let's concentrate on his breathing together.
戴好了
Yeah. All right. Here you go.
你会没事的  我们是急救人员
You got it. You're going to be all right, OK? We're the paramedics.
-你最好和我们一起走  -可是我的车
- You'd better come with us. - No, my car's -
我们不能丢下你  老兄  你跟我们一起
No, mate, we can't leave you. You're going to come with us.
麻烦你拿一下那个绿色的包
Bring that green bag, please.
一  二  三  抬
One, two, three, lift!
-好的  我们走  -走吧
- OK, let's go. - Go.
幸好有你朋友在  他用了肾上腺素笔
Lucky your friend was there. He used your EpiPen.
我们还备了些肾上腺素供你使用  没事
We've got some more adrenalin ready if you need it, all right?
一切都好  我知道现在呼吸很困难
Everything is OK. OK I know your breathing's not that easy,
我们五分钟之内就会到医院
but we'll be in the hospital in five minutes, OK?
坚持住  眼睛睁开
Hang on there. Just open your eyes.
胸外按压
Chest compressions!
注射一毫克肾上腺素
OK, we've got one milligram of adrenalin.
很好  好的  老兄
OK, well done. All right, mate...
介意我把窗户打开吗
Mind if I open a window?
我有点想吐
I think I'm going to be sick.
他的心搏停止了
He's arrested in the back!
心搏停止了
Arrested!
威廉·伯顿
William Burton?
请过来一下
Will you come with me, please?
你和福伊尔先生之间发生了什么事情吗
Did you and Mr. Foyle have any interactions?
是的
Yes.
他袭击了我  然后我刺伤了他
He attacked me and I stabbed him.
用这把刀
With this...
真让人吃惊啊  对吧
Quite a shock, don't you think?
什么意思
What is?
shad0刑事律师因谋杀罪被起诉
他死了
He's dead?
往下看
Keep reading.
打扰一下  瓦迪姆·库马因还在这儿工作吗
Excuse me. Erm, does Vadim Kumarin still work here?
你知道他现在人在哪儿吗  你知道
Do you know where he might be? Do you know...
好吧
Ok.
谢谢
Thank you.
欢迎来到苏格兰
Welcome to Scotland.
原来我在这里啊
Oh, is that where I am?!
怪不得周围都是苏格兰人
I wondered why everyone was Scottish.
从检察官那里传来好消息
Some good news from the fiscal.
如果你依照第76条
They'd recommend acceptance
承认杀人罪  他们乐于接受
if you offered a Section 76 plea of culpable homicide.
应该能减免三成的刑罚
Probably a 30 percent discount on sentence.
最多被判入狱九年  六年后就能出狱
That's nine years at most. Out in six.
你说是好消息  因为什么
And that's good news because...?
因为你现在麻烦缠身
Because you're in serious trouble.
你想做无罪申辩吗  这可是谋杀案的审判
If you're thinking of going not guilty, that's a murder trial!
公诉人会让你死无葬身之地的
The Crown's going to be all out for your blood.
听着  我替你起草了一份认罪书
Look, I typed up a draft plea offer for you.
这是一条出路
This is a choice.
你可以选择无期
You've got life,
因谋杀罪最少入狱二十年
with a minimum of 20 years for murder,
或者在这上面签字
or sign the offer,
六年就能出狱  还有机会看到你儿子毕业
do six years and see your son finish school,
而不是完全错过他的成长
instead of missing the whole thing.
我一分一秒都不会错过
I'm not missing a single second!
不要这样  冷静点
Don't be like this. Come on.
你得认真考虑下我的话
You need to seriously consider this.
-你认为人是我杀的吗  -当然不
- Do you think I did it? - No!
不是
No.
我当然不这么想
Of course I don't.
确保你把这张纸扔了
Make sure you recycle that.
很感谢你过来  詹妮
I appreciate you coming down, Jen,
但我会为自己辩护
but I think I'll do it myself.
-你不能这么做  -我可以
- You can't.  - I can.
我完全可以胜任
In fact, I can do all of it myself.
不  你不行
No, you can't!
这里是苏格兰法律  你个笨蛋
This is Scots Law, idiot.
跟你所学的完全不一样
There's a thousand differences.
《兰顿和布朗  刑事诉讼程序》对吧
Renton & Brown, right?
突击看一下就行
That's a punchy read.
你一直在努力帮我
You've always been there for me,
但很抱歉  我不需要你为我辩护
and I'm sorry, but this isn't going to work out.
你知道自己在干什么吗
What do you think you are doing? Eh?
-我是想帮你  -我知道
- I'm trying to help you here! - I know.
谢谢你
Thank you,
但我自己来就行
but I'll take it from here.
起立
Court!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
今天提起的公诉如下
the charge on the indictment is that,
3月23日  在苏格兰奥弗顿市旁
on the 23rd of March, at a house near Overton
克尔德森林中的一所房子内
in Kielder Forests in Scotland,
威廉·伯顿袭击了利亚姆·迈克尔·福伊尔
William Burton did assault Liam Michael Foyle
并用一把小刀刺伤了受害者
and did stab on the body with a knife
刀上含有一种物质
containing thereon a substance,
能对接受者造成严重伤害  即过敏反应
knowing that this would cause severe injury, anaphylaxis
并导致其死亡
and death to the recipient,
正是他谋杀了受害者
and he did murder him.
皇家检察署正式起诉威廉·伯顿
Call the Diet of Her Majesty's advocate against William Burton.
在苏格兰法庭上不用做开庭致辞  伯顿先生
We have no opening speeches in Scottish courts, Mr. Burton,
以防你有打算开始演说
just in case you were planning on making one at this stage.
是吗
Really?
伯顿先生  有人曾强烈劝说过你
Mr. Burton, you know you have been strongly advised
不要为自己辩护
against representing yourself.
我很清楚  法官阁下
It's been made very clear, My Lord.
很好
Very well.
我能把材料拿到律师席吗
Er, can I move my papers to the table?
不行
No.
我在被告席上不太方便辩护  可以理解吧
I can't very well run my case from the dock, can I?
伯顿先生  那正是你将要做的
That, Mr. Burton, is exactly what you are going to do.
你在搞什么
What are you doing?
-这种过敏症很常见吗  -不常见
- Is this a common allergy? - Not really.
患者只对一种腹足类动物过敏
It's an allergy to a particular gastropod.
即笠贝
Specifically, limpets.
他对笠贝严重过敏吗
He was deathly allergic to limpets?
具体说
Well more specifically,
是一种叫原肌球蛋白的活性蛋白质
an active protein known as tropomyosin.
那过敏原是从哪里来的
And where was this allergen?
福伊尔先生是怎么接触到的
How did Mr. Foyle come into contact with it?
伤口附近的局部肿胀说明
Localised swelling at the wound site suggest
应该是他死前被刺伤时
it may have been present on the weapon
由凶器进入他体内的
used to injure him before he died.
谢谢你  医生
Thank you, doctor.
伯顿先生
Mr Burton?
没有问题  谢谢法官阁下
No, thank you, My Lord.
伯顿先生  你想必清楚
Mr Burton, you are aware, of course,
一旦你为自己作证
that once you give evidence on your own behalf,
你需要接受检察官的交叉询问
you are opening yourself up to cross-examination by the Crown?
非常清楚  法官阁下
Very well aware, My Lord.
-现在呢  -可以拿出来了
- "What now?" - "OK, you can take it out.
看下针管  能看到红色长条吗
"Look at the barrel. Is there a red strip visible on the barrel?
有的话就说明药剂打进去了
"That will tell you that the drug went in."
稍等下
"Er, hang on. Hang on.
我看不清
"I can't see it!"
刻度上方有个小窗
"Just above the writing, there's a window."
没错  找到了  在这儿
"Oh, yes! Yes, yes, yes, it's there!"
病人有反应吗
"Is the patient responding?"
先生  先生  还在吗  有人在听吗
"Sir? Sir? Hello? Anybody hear me?"
这期间你似乎非常冷静
You appear to be very calm during this interaction.
-是不是  -我试图保持冷静
- Were you? - I was trying to be.
你在克尔德森林做什么  伯顿先生
What were you doing in Kielder Forest, Mr Burton?
我在卡莱尔面试工作
I had a job interview in Carlisle.
面试官建议我四处转转
The person I spoke to suggested I tour around a bit.
你参加面试时都带着刀吗
Do you normally conduct job interviews with a knife?
我娶了一把刀
I got married with a knife.
每个穿短裙的苏格兰人都娶了一把刀
Every Scotsman worth his kilt gets married with a knife.
你遇见福伊尔先生纯属巧合吗
You bumped into Mr Foyle by pure chance?
是的  我在一家酒吧看见他
Yes. I saw him in a pub
我迫切地感到应该和他谈谈
and I felt compelled to confront him.
你找到了他  想要他认罪
You sought him out to force a confession.
对不对
Isn't that correct?
是的
Yes.
-是吗  -是的  没错
- Yes? - Yes, that's right.
一罪不二审  哪怕是有新证据
Double jeopardy law, pertaining to new evidence.
我认为伯顿先生已经回答了你的问题
I believe Mr Burton has answered the question.
法官阁下
My Lord.
要他认罪
A confession -
这是你最大的愿望
something that you would've desired very much.
-是的  -当他拒绝了你的要求
- Yes. - And yet when he denied you this request,
你就杀了他
you took his life.
-没有  -你勃然大怒
- No. - You flew into a rage
用小刀袭击了他  对不对
and attacked him with a knife, didn't you?
-你说什么时候  -你用小刀砍伤了他
- When was this, sorry? - When you slashed him with the knife,
你在供词里说得很清楚
as you've said clearly in your statement!
是啊  在我把他背出火场之前
Oh, yes, before I carried him out of a burning building.
伯顿先生
Mr Burton!
我只是确认一下时间先后
Just being clear on chronology.
你是在耍小聪明
Flying close to the sun.
腹足类动物过敏
A gastropod allergy,
一种贝类
a specific kind of shellfish -
这不是轻易能得到的信息
not exactly easy information to find out.
我同意
No, I'd imagine not.
你看过委托人的医疗记录吗
Have you ever had cause to access a client's medical records?
看过  如果与案件有关的话
Yes, though only if pertinent to the case.
桑德拉·马林斯一案中
In the case of Sandra Mullins,
-你曾为福伊尔先生辩护  -是的
- you were lead counsel for Mr Foyle's defence. - I was.
你调查过福伊尔先生的医疗信息吗
Did you ever request any medical information regarding Mr Foyle?
-没有  -没有吗
- No. - You did not?
没有  我没接触过这类文件
No, I did not access his files.
我认为他的回答足够充分
I believe his "No" was sufficient.
法官阁下  你显然无法证明这点
My Lord. You cannot prove this, of course.
他是你的委托人
He was your client.
你对他的资料非常了解
You were intimately acquainted with his information.
不  机密医疗文件
No. Erm... Confidential medical files are
全部数字化  被安全保存在事务律师那里
all digitised and kept securely at the solicitors,
想必在他的医生和医院也同样安全
or, presumably, equally securely at his doctors or hospital.
啰嗦这么多  我其实是说没有
Which is a long-winded way of saying no,
我没看过他的医疗记录
I did not access his files,
而且  我可以证明
and, yes, I can prove it.
伯顿先生想要的
What Mr Burton is asking of you
非常简单  女士们先生们
is very simple, ladies and gentlemen.
他想让你们相信他编的故事
He wants you to believe his little story.
他想让你们相信
He wants you to believe
一切都是命运的作弄
that through an ironic twist of fate,
那把错误的小刀
this was the wrong knife,
在错误的人手里
in the wrong hand,
闯进了错误的时间
at the wrong time.
我敬告各位
I respectfully submit to you
他说的一切纯属虚构
that this is pure fabrication.
这种先见之明  有着恶毒的目的
This was foreknowledge, with malicious intent.
随他怎么说  但我要问
He will tell you otherwise, but I ask only this question -
他讲了个动听的故事
he tells a good story,
但我们真的相信他吗
but do we really believe him?
我是个律师
I'm a lawyer.
我一生信奉法律
I have lived and believed in the law all my life.
但当法律降临在你头上
But until the law happens to you,
相信我  你会无所适从
believe me, you don't know which way you're going to go.
我在小屋面对面见到的那个人
The man I faced in that cabin
就是谋杀我妻子的凶手  这毫无疑问
is the man I know, beyond all doubt, murdered my wife.
面对这个人  我本可以有很多选择
I could've done a lot of things to him.
但是
Instead,
我看到了他的痛苦  为他叫了救护车
I saw him suffer and I called an ambulance.
我挽救他于危险之中
I removed him from danger.
我做了所有正派人都会做的事情
I did what any decent human being should do.
但请不要误会  我做这些事情
But make no mistake, I did those things
仅仅是出于基本的良心和纯粹的道义
out of nothing more than a sincere duty to our common decency.
我这么做  因为这是世上每一个人
I did so because that's what's expected
所应当做的
when you're a person in the world.
我冒险救的这个人  他带走了我的挚爱
I risked my life to save the man who took away my heart...
我人生的向导
..my compass,
我生活的重心
my anchor,
也是我最好的朋友
my best friend.
他在我面前倒下时  我手里正有一把刀
I faced him down with a knife in my hand,
我本可以任他烧死
I could've let him burn!
在这种情况下  我相信
In the circumstances, I believe
我表现出了非凡的克制力
I exerted an extraordinary amount of restraint.
利亚姆·福伊尔死了
Liam Foyle is dead.
我对他的死亡感到高兴
I rejoice in his passing.
但是你不能说我是谋杀他的凶手
But you should not convict me of his murder.
-威尔  -这个是你的
- Will! - That's your one.
威尔
Will.
你好
Oh, hi!
很意外
OK, interesting...
我想和你谈谈
I wanted to talk to you.
如果我是你就快点说
I'd hurry up if I were you,
你知道陪审团什么样
you know what juries can be like.
他们不可能深思熟虑
They can't deliberate forever.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我感觉怎么样
How am I feeling?
当你知道发生的事情后
When you heard what happened.
拜托  你没有一点释然的感觉吗
Come on, you weren't just a wee bit relieved?
我需要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
-精神支持吗  -是法律意见
- Moral support? - Legal advice.
我一直纠结于一个案子  真的让我很头疼
I've been grappling with a case that's been bothering me,
不知道你能不能帮帮我
and wondered if you could help.
我马上回来
Be right back.
说吧
Shoot.
前几天我想起了一些事
Something occurred to me the other day...
如果你想打开保险箱
If you wanted to break into a safe,
你第一个要找的人就是锁匠
the first person you'd call is a locksmith, and, um,
如果你想谋杀又想脱罪的话
if you wanted to commit murder and get away with it,
你也许希望和一个刑事律师谈谈
you might just want to talk to a criminal barrister.
这是个有趣的想法
That's an interesting idea.
我看过了太多的案件
I see enough cases turn on
最后发现完美的犯罪之所以完美
discovery to know that a perfect crime only stays perfect
是因为它们看似显而易见  对吗
if it's done in plain sight, wouldn't you say?
可能吧
Could be.
可能所有人都知道真相了  但还是不知道
Everyone would have all the facts and still have no idea
他到底是怎么做的
how he really did it.
第一步  他找到了要害
Step one - he'd find the Achilles heel.
致命的过敏症  很罕见的一种
A deathly allergy, say. A rare one.
这个人是怎么发现这件事的
How did this person find out something like that?
刑事律师整天都在做什么
What does a criminal barrister do all day long?
-追踪单据  -和犯人谈话
- Chase invoices. - Talk to criminals.
这不就可以有一本通讯簿
Wouldn't that give him an address book,
写满了潜在的线人吗
full of potential contacts?
以我现在正在办的案子为例
For example, on the case that I'm working on,
有人目击到嫌疑人和一个人尽皆知的罪犯谈话
the man was seen talking to a known criminal.
怎么确定那个人是他  我是说那个罪犯
How would the person be sure it was him? The criminal, I mean.
当然了  我假设是男的
Presuming it was a he, of course...
他对目击者来说很熟悉
He was well-known to the eyewitness.
但是当时是白天还是晚上呢
Yeah, but was it day or night?
他是步行还是在车里
Was he on foot, in a vehicle?
目击者有没有承受任何压力
Was the observer under any stress at all?
第二步
Step two -
假设他找到了一个天然的过敏原
what if he found a natural-occurring source for the allergen,
在一个平凡而又日常的去处
somewhere innocent and every day?
如果他们想被判正当防卫
If they argue self-defence,
他们可能会给凶器装载过敏原
they might load up a weapon with that allergen
达到一定剂量
to administer the dose.
我听着呢
I'm with you so far.
但是要完全依靠
But to put so much weight on one
一个剂量的过敏原是不够的  你认为呢
dose of allergen might not be enough, don't you think?
我压根就不了解这件事
I wouldn't know the first thing about it.
第三步
Step three -
过敏症会引起过敏反应  而患有
these people with allergies of such severity
如此严重过敏症的人
that they cause anaphylaxis,
他们都会随身携带一种救命的笔状注射剂
they carry these little life-saving pens with them,
叫做肾上腺素笔  对吗
don't they, called EpiPens?
你觉得有没有可能将救命的笔
Do you think it might be possible
变成一支致命的笔呢
to repurpose a pen as a poison pen?
用含有过敏原的注射剂
By replacing the carrier solution
替换原来的注射剂
with a solution of allergen,
那人就能破坏挽救生命的急救药物
a person might sabotage the very thing that would save a person's life.
-这太恶毒了  -可不是吗
- That sounds diabolical. - It does, doesn't it?
-这是法律问题  -如果那个人拨打999
- You mentioned a legal question. - And if that person called 999,
999  紧急电话
应急中心接线员说
and the emergency services said they
他们在对死者使用注射笔时一直在交谈
talked them through administering that pen to the victim,
这可以说就是合谋作案
it's almost collusion in the crime.
他们那是在帮助凶手一步一步完成谋杀
They'd be walking that person, step by step, through the murder.
你是指他们有电话录音备份
Oh, you mean they'd have a public record of the conversation.
-是的  -啊  可能有用
- Yes. - Ah, that might fly.
但不会真有人这么干吧
But I really don't think anyone would seriously attempt it.
-为什么  -谋杀是犯法的
- Why not? - I think murder's against the law!
上次我亲眼所见
I mean, last time I looked...
-威尔  -你画出了界线  一条大红线
- Will... - You're drawing a line. A big red one.
知道界线的存在
There's a huge difference between
和跨过界线的差别是很巨大的
knowing where that line is and stepping over it.
我知道我不会
I know I couldn't.
为什么
Why not?
我害怕被抓住
I'd be scared of getting caught.
-你刚说这是完美犯罪  -是的
- You just said it was the perfect crime. - Oh, it is!
是啊
It is.
除了三点
Except for three things...
三点
Three?
是吗
Really?
第一
One -
处理凶器
disposing the weapon.
有两支肾上腺素注射笔  其中一支是凶器
There'd be two EpiPens, the innocent one and the murder weapon.
凶手在现场将正常的那支笔放电
The killer would have to discharge the innocent EpiPen at the locus
造成被使用的假象
so it looked like he'd done
就好像他真的按照接线员的提示做了
what he talked to the emergency services about.
接下来  我推测
Then I imagine he'd have to chuck
他必须把下过毒的注射笔扔进锐物垃圾袋
the poisoned EpiPen into the sharps disposal bags.
但还是有可能
But there's a chance it could be found
在烧毁前被警察搜到
before being incinerated if the police do a search.
很聪明
Ah! Very clever.
第二  事先需要弄到注射笔
Two - obtaining the pen in the first place.
他必须认识某个已经拿到处方的人
He'd have to know someone with a... with a prescription already.
说得好
Hm... Good point.
接下来是第三点
Oh, and then there's number three...
患者免疫球蛋白过敏
"Patient suffered IgE phylum Mollusca allergy,
引发支气管痉挛和过敏反应
"severe bronchospasm and anaphylaxis and..."
"另据观察"  这是写在脚注里的
under 'Additional Observations', hidden away in the footnotes,
局部肿胀的部位有伤口
"..Some local swelling at wound...
和注射部位
"..And injection site".
你知道他们不会查死者的肾上腺素
But, you know, they don't test for epinephrine after death,
所以无从得知注射笔是否真的被使用
so there's no way of knowing if the EpiPen had been used or not,
除了通过针孔判断
except for the puncture wound.
我的第三点就是
So my number three is this -
再次对注射孔进行组织学检查
risk of a follow-up histology on local puncture site.
你很有想象力
You have a very creative mind.
如果那人知道随时会进行尸检
But would that person be able to sleep soundly,
在针孔处分析过敏原
knowing that at any moment, there might be another post-mortem
他还能睡踏实吗
that identified allergen at the EpiPen site?
那要看情况
Well, I guess that depends...
什么情况
On what?
尸体是否火化
On whether the body's been cremated...
陪审团主席请起立
Can the foreman stand, please?
-你们达成裁决了吗  -是的
- Have you reached a verdict? - We have.
对于皇家检察署起诉威廉·伯顿犯谋杀罪一案
In the case of Her Majesty's Advocate against William Burton,
你们认为谋杀罪名是否成立
how do you find the accused on the charge of murder?
证据不足
Not proven.
好
Yes!
肃静
Silence, please!
伯顿先生  你有何感想  伯顿先生
Mr Burton! Mr Burton! Any comments, Mr Burton?
证据不足
Not proven, of course,
苏格兰法律的第三裁决生效
the third verdict available in Scottish law.
最终无罪释放
Effectively an acquittal,
但这仍然说明有犯罪...
but one which suggests a suspicion of guilt...
你认为自己能
Do you think you would've got away
逃脱英国的法律吗  伯顿先生
with it in an English court of law? Mr Burton!
-保重  -你怎么看  伯顿先生
- Take care. - What have you got to say, Mr Burton?
好了
Ok...
低一点
..Hold it down.
shad2脱 罪 大 师
第一季  第三集
YYeTs人人影视英剧社倾情奉献
bei1翻译  DT的宠物熊猫  爱卿遛小鸟
bei1翻译  Silmar  噎死青春
bei1翻译  死跑龙套的  面条打包子
bei1翻译  蜂蜜柠檬  泰斯
bei1时间轴  吉吉  今  狱
bei1特别鸣谢  POTO的小饭桶
bei1特效&后期   sweet宝宝88
bei1总监   泰斯·雪诺
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com